Timothy Lyon

Enterprise Database Administrator/ PeopleSoft Administrator

Summary

Sr. Database Administrator with extensive experience in implementing, configuring, & administering PeopleSoft Enterprise Applications on SQL/ Oracle Databases. Expert level Database Management, Tuning, & Upgrading.

Successfully performed several Implementations, Upgrades; Regular Maintenance/ Service Packs, & Patches (Change Assistant/ PUM/ DPKs). In depth experience PeopleSoft/ Database Security as well as a strong background managing multiple internal & external Integrations via Integration Broker/ Application Messaging.

Experience

Senior Database Administrator; PeopleSoft Administrator

January 2011 - Present

Database Administrator & PeopleSoft Administrator supporting HCM 9.1 & Finance 9.1 (PeopleTools 8.51, 8.54) for opening of new Adventist Healthcare Facility (Loma Linda University Medical Center - Murrieta). Managed post-implementation support for all PeopleSoft production & non-production environments including PeopleSoft administration, security, & maintenance. Manage, test, & implement Tax Updates/ Patches. Project Management/application through Dev, Cert, & Prod environments. Managed, configured Integration Broker for internal/external communication.

- Performed complete export of HCM & FSCM Oracle Databases, Application, & Middleware to Oracle Managed Cloud Services (Oracle DataPump) & acted as lead DBA for planning, testing, & implementation.
- Configured/ Re-configured Integration Broker & all Application Gateways/ Nodes/ Messaging for internal & external communication between HCM & Finance/ SCM within Oracle Cloud (https).
- Created/ configured numerous 3rd party interfaces within PeopleSoft (IB Nodes, Channels, Gateways Configuration), Excel to CI
- Managed PeopleSoft Security (Managed all User Profiles, Permission Lists, & Roles) w/ Single Sign-on, LDAP Authentication, Active Directory Sync

Sr. PeopleSoft Database Administrator at The American College

May 2009 - June 2010 (1 year 2 months)

Sr. PeopleSoft Database Administrator

PeopleSoft Administrator for Large College supporting & upgrading Production PeopleSoft. Responsible for architecting, designing & implementing Finance, CRM, & HCM 8.9 to 9.0 Application Upgrade. Responsible for architecting, designing, & implementing Portal 8.8 to 9.0 Application Upgrade. Responsible for architecting, designing, & implementing PeopleTools 8.44.08/8.46.04 to 8.49.22 Upgrade. Designed

the entire infrastructure, hardware for all Production & Non-Production environments. Implemented Integration Broker, Application Messaging, & Single Signon on multiple Tools versions. Responsible for architecting, designing & implementing SQL Server 2000 to 2005 upgrade for all Production & Non-Production databases. WebLogic 8.1/9.2, Tuxedo 8.1/9.1 administration. Applied Tax Updates, Bundles, & Service Packs. Support for Team of 8 PeopleSoft Technical & Functional Team members.

- Maintain, support, upgrade, & design entire PeopleSoft infrastructure (CRM, HCM, FIN, Portal)
- Senior PeopleSoft Technical contact for entire University
- Expert performance tuning on all aspects of all 3 tiers (Web Server, Application Server & Database)
- Disaster Recovery/Load Balancing/Fail Over on every level
- Expert Integration Broker/Application Messaging between multiple PeopleTools versions (8.44 8.49)

SQL/PeopleSoft Database Administrator at Fort Bend ISD

September 2007 - August 2008 (1 year)

SQL Server DBA contracted to support/improve/administer a post go-live PeopleSoft implementation (HCM 8.9, Finance 8.9, Enterprise Portal 8.9, CRM 8.9) (PeopleTools 8.47) Redesigned SQL Server 2005/2000 database architecture for both Production & non-production applications. Improved on-line processing & batch job processing in Production Finance by over 300% on 64 bit SQL Server 2005 Enterprise (Windows Server 2003 Enterprise x64). Improved on-line processing & batch processing in production HCM by over 150 %. Designed robust, reliable backup/disaster recovery plan for all environments. PeopleSoft upgrade patch maintenance (Service Packs, Maintenance Packs, Rollup Packs, Bundles, Tax Updates, etc). Provide DBA support for all 3 tiers of 4 production PeopleSoft environments (as well as several non-production development/test environments). Support PeopleSoft Functional & Technical team members.

PeopleSoft/SQL Server/Oracle Database Administrator at CIBER

January 2007 - July 2007 (7 months)

Consultant - Sr. PeopleSoft Admin / Database Administrator

PeopleSoft Admin/DBA (SQL/Oracle). Managed multiple short to mid term contracts for higher education institutions throughout the Continental United States & Canada. 100% travel.

Morain Park Technical College, Fond du Lac, WI

PeopleSoft DBA for PeopleSoft Student Administration 8.9# 9.0 upgrade. Support & continually update Financials 8.4, HRMS 8.9, CRM 8.8, Portal 8.8; Various Enterprise PeopleTools experience (PT8.22, 8.43, 8.45, 8.46-8.49). Large-scale database administration/management for multiple development, test, & production environments. Develop & document migration policies & procedures; PeopleSoft upgrade Patch maintenance (Service Packs, Maintenance Packs, Rollup Packs, Bundles, etc). Managed/Configured Integration Broker, Application Messaging, Node Configuration, Gateways, & Single Sign-on between multiple Tools releases. Support all 3 tiers of several PeopleSoft environments (application/web/process scheduler/reporting servers) running several modules. Strong WebLogic (6.x, 8.x, 9.x) /Tuxedo Middleware (8.x, 9.x) implementation & support including DST patch for 2007. Develop robust, reliable Disaster Recovery strategies for mission critical production/development databases. Support PeopleSoft Functional & Technical team members.

Peralta College, San Francisco, CA

PeopleSoft Database Administrator – Financials 8.9# 9.0 (PeopleTools 8.47 # 8.49.14) upgrade/ PeopleTools Upgrade. Applied patches to HR 9.0. Supported & updated BEA WebLogic & Tuxedo Middleware.

Database backup & disaster recovery for production & development environments.

Mira Costa College, San Diego, CA; Toronto, CA

Assisted with HCM 8.0 – HCM 9.0 application upgrade on Oracle database (Windows & Linux platforms). Installed PeopleSoft HCM 9.0 application on PeopleTools 8.49.03 (Oracle backend) as a Demo environment. Configured Application/Web Server/Process Scheduler/Report Repository.

SQL/PeopleSoft Database Administrator / Active Directory & Exchange Administrator at National University

February 2005 - December 2006 (1 year 11 months)

SQL DBA throughout PeopleSoft Enterprise Implementation. Implemented smooth transition from MIS mainframe to PeopleSoft on Windows 2K & 2K3. Significant exposure to PeopleSoft architecture, implementing HRSA 8.1SP2, Financial Supply Chain Management 8.4, 8.9, Customer Resource Management 8.81, & Portal 8.8 (PeopleTools 8.22.06, 8.43, 8.45, 8.47.03) in load balanced 2 & 3 tier (WebLogic 5, 6.1, 8.1) environment running SQL 2K on the backend. Responsibilities include database administration, configuration, maintenance & support, optimization, security, & backup strategies; monitoring database security, monitoring SQL jobs submitted, database performance tuning, backups, restores, & refreshes. Manage multiple domains, database sizing, creating & maintaining PeopleSoft environments. Strong PeopleSoft/SQL Server monitoring & database/app/web server tuning (Quest Foglight/Spotlight applications). Provide 24x7x365 support for all Production & Development systems.

Sr. Technical Consultant

July 2004 - January 2005 (7 months)

Technical IT Consulting for small to mid-size businesses. Designed network, security, file sharing, and email architecture. Setup & secure wired & wireless networks. Managed all accounting, budget, personnel, customer service, and all aspects of owning a small IT consulting business. Implemented small corporate networks & acted as IT support for several small businesses.

Sr. Systems Engineer (Windows Ops) - Consultant at PeopleSoft

June 2003 - December 2003 (7 months)

Directly managed purchase & configuration of all Intel Servers (IBM & HP) throughout PeopleSoft acquisition & integration. Heavy Performance Monitoring (Processor, Memory, Disk) of multiple Windows Servers; proposed & signed off on replacement servers & hardware for several applications (Email, Domain Controllers, Database, File & Application Servers). Directly oversaw purchase of all Intel server hardware for all projects for US & Canada offices, and acted as Sr. Technical resource for all projects in over 30 additional countries. All in-house & field servers on a 3 yr life-cycle.

Sr. Systems Administrator at Deloitte

October 2002 - March 2003 (6 months)

Technical Project Lead - Consultant

Consultant responsible for the migration of 400+ application servers from one Production Active Directory Domain into another. Product Evaluation, Multiple Vendor Communication (Bindview, NetIQ, VMWare)Technical Planning (DNS, WINS, DHCP, Group Policy, etc.), Documentation, follow-through, and coordination with application teams for PeopleSoft/JD Edwards Application testing in Lab environment. Coordination with Global Messaging team, Account Migration Team, and Network Architecture team to perform a secure migration, transparent to end user. (Approximately 150,000 clients) Heavy use of ADMT, NetIQ DMA, VMware, Active Directory structure, Compaq Proliant G2 and IBM X Series Servers.

Sr. Systems Administrator at Independence Blue Cross

January 2002 - August 2002 (8 months)

Sr. Systems Administrator - Consultant

Consultant administering all aspects of NT/2000 Server Production, Security, maintenance/upgrades, data integrity/security, Multiple NT Domain administration, Active Directory migration & administration. Project Management and heavy 3rd party vendor communication for high-end Application implementation into extremely complex environment of 8400 users, 200+ servers. Primary contact for all NAV server protection & automated updates to all Independence Blue Cross Servers. Compaq, IBM, and Dell series servers.

Sr. Network Administrator/ Mgr of Tech Services at Fairbanks Capital

August 2000 - December 2001 (1 year 5 months)

Designed & managed all technical services rendered in a 500+ user, Windows 2000 Active Directory network laying the architecture from the ground up. Implementation & oversight of all day-to-day network functions for all mission critical systems. Managed implementation includes Active Directory admin. & Exchange 2000 integration, AD Group Policy & Profile implementation, AD DNS registration, data backup, integrity & protection strategy, anti-virus strategy, TCP/IP addressing schematics & sub netting, server hardware & software maintenance/upgrades, firewall & proxy server admin., external DNS registration, Cisco Switch & Router admin., AS400 end user functionality config. app-to-wkstn roll-out, Host Int. Server implementation (configuration & administration); Primary contact for all vendor communication. Manage all Information Technology Departmental Planning, reporting, training, legal, staffing issues for Hatboro office while acting in the capacity of lead technical contact (24x7x365) for all issues. Coordinate the efforts of a staff of 4 PC/Helpdesk Technicians.

Sr. Network Administrator/ Mgr of Tech. Services at Osprey

January 1999 - August 2000 (1 year 8 months)

Maintained and coordinated all IT related functions for an organization with 15+ servers, and 400 clients in a mixed NT/Novell/Win2K LAN/WAN environment. Implementation & oversight of all day-to-day network functions for all mission critical systems. Primary contact for all Information Technology issues, such as hardware/software implementation/upgrades, network security & backups, router/dsu/csu/switch/hub administration, firewall/proxy server administration, vendor communication & purchasing,

user maintenance, Help Desk management, and all server-related responsibilities. Managed NT/2K department planning, projects, staffing, & training. Oversee NYC & Chicago offices as well & all Wide area communications/ issues with them. Coordinated/managed the efforts of a staff of 5 PC/Network technicians.

Education

National University

Information Technology

Activities and Societies: Various Courses; PeopleTools Administration

East Stroudsburg University of Pennsylvania

Associates, Information Technology

Northampton Community College

Various Certifications, Networking, LAN Administration

University of Phoenix

Bachelors, Information Technology

Timothy Lyon

Enterprise Database Administrator/ PeopleSoft Administrator



Contact Timothy on LinkedIn